A Guide to the Papers of Harold Frederic, 1886-1899
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Harold Frederic, 1886-1899
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7588
This collection consists of 14 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 10 June 1964.
Scope and Content Information
Collection includes 10 letters written by Frederic from 1886 through 1897, primarily concerning his writing, both of literary works and articles. His works mentioned include: "Seth's Brother's Wife," an article on Gladstone, an unidentified "A Boy's Story," "Illumination, "In the Valley," and "Stamp Album." The letters mention his collaboration with Barrymore on a play and his hope for financial independence.
Also in his letters, Frederic makes a request for inside information for a New York Times article; and supplies information on the Klock family. Correspondents include: John Howe; editor of Life;S.S. McClure; Sampson, Low, Marston and Company; and C.F. Keary.
Collection also contains photograph of Frederic, which accompanied a letter; photograph of his last will and testament dated August 17, 1898; negative photograph of the registration of his will dated January 11, 1899; and negative photograph of Grace Frederic's will dated June 7, 1899.
Contents List
- Letters
  - Harold Frederic to "Boy" [John Howe] 1886 Feb 27, ALS. 8pp.
  - H.F. to Editor of Life1887 Mar 8, ALS. 4pp.
  - H.F. to McClure 1894 Feb 7, ALS. 2pp.
  - H.F. to McClure with clipping of photograph of H.F. attached 1894 Mar 14, ALS. 2pp.
  - H.F. to Messrs. Sampson Low, Marstow and Co. 1895 Dec 10, ALS. 2pp.
  - H.F. to Russell [1896 June 15](Monday evening), ALS. 2pp.
  - H.F. to Russell 1896 Dec 21, ALS. 1p.
  - H.F. to Sir [Klock?] 1897 Dec 31, ALS. 2pp.
  - H.F. to Mr. Keary [ ] Jan 28. Tuesday, ALS. 2pp.
  - H.F. to Ada [ ] Thursday afternoon, ALS. 1p.
- Miscelleous
  - Transcript of Will and Testament of H.F. 1898 Aug 17, Photograph
  - Extract from the Principal Probate Registry of the High Court of Justice (England) re: the the will of H.F. 1899 Jan 11, Negative photograph
  - Extract from the Principle Probate Registry of the High Court of Justice (England) re: will of Grace Frederic, ca. 1899 Mar, Negative photograph of typescript (positive)
  - 39 Bedford Square, London n.d., Photograph
  - 2 photographs of "Homefield" (Frederic's home in Surrey, England) n.d., Photographs